<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
<name>Unlock Player Factions</name>
<author>Aethaeran</author>
<url>https://ludeon.com/forums/index.php</url>
<targetVersion>0.19.2009</targetVersion>
<description>Unlocks the normally inaccessible Tech Levels from within the 'player faction' section of the scenario editor.
The higher the tech level is on the 'player faction' list, the slower it researches.
Though it should be mentioned, the research speed of everything from Industrial to Archotech is identical. 
This cannot be changed unless I edit the games assemblies, or the tech levels of the researches themselves.
For cross-mod-compatibility sake as well as straying too far from vanilla I would like to avoid this.
It is also my understanding that the starting Tech Level of your faction also effect gear pawns can be spawned with, though I am not quite sure of the specifics behind this.
The "(No Research)" starting factions are identical to their counterparts except that they all start without ANY technologies unlocked.

The New Player Factions
=======================

New Undefined Faction
---------------------
-This is technically a no research start, but I wanted to mark it differently in case I decide to add starting researches to it.
techLevel = Undefined
backstoryCategories = Tribal
hairTags = Tribal
apparelStuffFilter = Cloth

New Animal Faction
------------------
-This is technically a no research start, but I wanted to mark it differently in case I decide to add starting researches to it.
techLevel = Animal
backstoryCategories = Tribal
hairTags = Tribal
apparelStuffFilter = Cloth

New Neolithic Faction
------------------
-Starts with all Neolithic techLevel researches completed.
techLevel = Neolithic
backstoryCategories = Tribal
hairTags = Tribal
apparelStuffFilter = Cloth

New Medieval Faction
------------------
-Starts with all Neolithic and Medieval techLevel researches completed.
techLevel = Medieval
backstoryCategories = Civil
hairTags = Rural
apparelStuffFilter = Cloth

New Industrial Faction
------------------
-Starts with all Neolithic and Medieval techLevels researches completed as well as the Machining line.
techLevel = Industrial
backstoryCategories = Civil
hairTags = Urban
apparelStuffFilter = Synthread

New Spacer Faction
------------------
-Starts with all researches up to and including Microelectronics completed.
techLevel = Spacer
backstoryCategories = Traveler
hairTags = Urban
apparelStuffFilter = DevilstrandCloth

New Ultra Faction
------------------
-Starts with all researches up to and including MultiAnalyzer completed.
techLevel = Ultra
backstoryCategories = Traveler
hairTags = Urban
apparelStuffFilter = Hyperweave

New Archotech Faction
------------------
-Starts with all researches up to but EXCLUDING Starflight Basics completed.
techLevel = Archotech
backstoryCategories = Traveler
hairTags = Urban
apparelStuffFilter = Hyperweave

New Starflight Faction
------------------
-Starts with every single vanilla research completed.
techLevel = Archotech
backstoryCategories = Traveler
hairTags = Urban
apparelStuffFilter = Hyperweave

LICENSE

Free. As in free beer. Copy, learn and be respectful.
</description>
</ModMetaData>
